Thank You, Lord.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Glory be to God.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
Viewers, we salute your faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated, thank you.
I know today, the Spirit of God will talk to you.
Hallelujah!
Let's quickly take our Bible to the Book of John.
John 14; I will take my proof text from John 14, the rest of the Book will be given to you.
“ ‘Do not let your heart be troubled…”
I told you about the word ‘heart’, it is your spirit they refer to.
Wherever you see the word ‘heart’, it means your spirit, biblically.
It refers to your spirit – man’s spirit.
“ ‘Do not let your hearts be troubled. You believe in God…"
Without heart, you cannot have anything to do with God – without spirit.
He uses our spirit to get to us.
The spirit of God uses our spirit to talk to us.
This is why you see 'heart'.
“ ‘Do not let your hearts be troubled. You believe in God; believe also in me.
My Father’s house has many mansions;
if that were not so, would I have told you that I am going there to prepare a place for you?' "
It means there are so many mansions, big mansions,
that is why He is going there to prepare a place for you; there will be an accommodation for you.
Let's go to the verse 26, which is the proof text.
“But the Advocate, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name,
will teach you all things and will remind you of everything I have said to you.”
That is the Holy Spirit.
Go back to that Book of John 14, Acts 16:7 and Luke 24:47.
That would be very good.
Also the Book of Ephesians 4:30.
In that John 14:26: "But the Advocate, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name,
will teach you all things and will remind you of everything I have said to you.”
It means without that Holy Spirit, you cannot remember anything of Jesus.
This means, if you are not born of the Spirit, you are not born again.
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a true believer.
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a true Christian.
That is why there is a fashion today - they call religion one, they call Christianity the other.
You just choose where you want to belong - to religious people, or to Christianity.
Christianity lies in the heart.
Our heart is the contact point; it is the communication point.
That is Christianity for you.
He came to restore the relationship and fellowship between you and God.
Religious people believe they must go there
but our God came to restore the relationship and fellowship between you and God.
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not born again.
You are not born again, you are not a Christian, you are not a true believer.
How can you be born of the Spirit
because our God is Spirit and His worshippers must do so in Spirit and truth.
That is why you have to be born of the Spirit.
Going by that Book of John 14:26,
and the Book of Ephesians 4:30,
you will find those key messages, and in Acts 16:6-7.
The Holy Spirit is a Divine Person.
Take note of that.
If the Holy Spirit is a Divine Person, who is standing here?
Is it T.B. Joshua that is talking to you, or the Divine Person?
In you - Divine Person, if you are a Christian, believer, born-again.
I'm here, T.B. Joshua and the Divine Person is standing before you, but you don't know who is talking to you.
What happens will determine.
When the Divine Person talks, changes are beginning.
It means I'm here, but the appearance you are seeing is Mr. T.B. Joshua.
We have two natures in one person – the divine and human.
The Holy Spirit is a Divine Person.
This Divine Person we obtain as a gift from God upon repentance and baptism.
If you have not repented, you cannot receive that Divine Person.
You will stand to be preaching, not the Divine Person.
You have the ability to preach; Divine Person, the Holy Spirit preaches as He wills.
You have the ability, charismatic, you can talk but the Holy Spirit also talks as He wills.
When the Holy Spirit talks, changes are beginning.
This Divine Person we obtain, we receive as a gift from God, freely from God,
upon repentance and baptism.
What is repentance?
That is the question.
Repentance means, being deeply sorry for sin.
I mean, being committed to a new way of life, from unfaithfulness to faithfulness;
being committed to a new way of life – from disobedience to obedience, from hate to love,
from unrighteousness to righteousness.
Being committed to a new way of life, that of serving God, following God
which comes when God’s Spirit begins to live in us.
You cannot do it; no one can do the work of the Cross, only God can.
You say, "I want to be obedient".
You want to be obedient?
You can be obedient to yourself but to be obedient to God, you need the Spirit of God.
This obedience comes when God’s Spirit begins to live in us.
The more you meditate, the more your heart acts upon the Word of God.
You can preach, I can preach but the Holy Spirit preaches as He wills.
When the Holy Spirit preaches, changes are beginning.
The words we speak in prayer, in counselling,
if they are not according to the true Word of God,
I mean if they are not according to the Spirit of God,
they will be idle, meaningless and often times destructive.
Because when you call the name 'Jesus', and you are not calling this name by the help of the Holy Ghost;
when satan hears it - that name is like an eagle.
When there is an eagle flying, moving around, you see some chicken moving around;
you see the chicken running for shelter.
Just the same name 'Jesus' - satan does not even want to hear that named called -
whether that name is called with the help of the Holy Ghost but mere hearing that name 'Jesus!'...
If they now realise that you are calling that name by yourself, not by the help of the Holy Ghost -
they get you arrested, beating you.
This is what happened to the seven sons of Sceva.
It is like you see a tiger, or lion and you don't know whether it is tied down.
Mere seeing lion - my brother, what will you do?
You don't want to know whether it is tied down or not - you run for your dear life.
Before you know the lion was tied down, you have disappeared.
In the same way the name 'Jesus' - when satan hears 'Jesus', "Who is calling the name 'Jesus'?"
By the time they sight you and they realise that the name you are calling
is not by the help of the Holy Ghost, you will pay dearly for it.
This is exactly what happened to the seven sons of Sceva.
The words we speak in prayer - "In Jesus' name!", "Be healed!" - in counselling, in teaching,
if they are not according to the true Word of God, if they are not according to the Spirit of God,
they will be idle and oftentimes destructive – very dangerous.
The Bible says in Luke 24:47, ‘Repentance allows us to receive a new life from God’.
Repentance allows us to receive what?
Talk to me!
[- A new life.]
What allows you to receive a new life?
[-Repentance.]
Repentance.
What is that new life?
Repentance is our only hope of receiving God’s mercy.
We have the Holy Spirit because God’s Word plainly so indicates,
not because of some emotional sensation.
"I have received the Holy Spirit..."
Not because of some emotional sensation.
We have the Holy Spirit because God’s Word plainly so indicates.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"It is the Holy Spirit" - what kind of Holy Spirit?
Manifestation.
Not because of some emotional sensation, but because God's Word plainly so indicates.
In 1 Thessalonians 5:23, we are told that man is a divine being, spirit being.
The real thing about man is not his body but his spirit.
Man is a spirit being.
The real thing about you...
Tell your neighbour;
The real thing about me is not my body.
When we wake up in the morning, you make up, do your hair, look in the mirror -
you have forgotten the real thing.
You have forgotten to dress the real thing.
You have forgotten to make up for the real thing.
You have forgotten to put more hair, wig for the real thing.
You have forgotten the real thing.
Whom are we supposed to take care of first?
The real thing - tell your neighbour - should be the first priority.
You are supposed to take care of the real thing;
bath the real thing, make up for the real thing, take care of the real thing.
The real thing about you is not your body but your spirit.
Today, what are you taking care of?
Tell me how many times you have looked in the mirror and you saw the real thing,
and you know how it looks like.
Some of us look good, beautiful, handsome, but if you look at your real thing -
this is the way you look because we are not taking care of it.
Some of your real things look like...
And you look beautiful.
Sometimes, when I see people moving around, "Hi";
when I look at him to know the real thing in him, the real thing looks like...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, “You will be very embarrassed when you see your real thing”.
Can you see the life we are living?
You would be very embarrassed, if God showed you your real thing.
Some of the real things look like this...
But you - you look beautiful, handsome.
You make up in the morning, you wake up, you take care of yourself, you do your teeth.
You say, "Can you get me salad?"
Have you fed your real thing?
"Salad, do you have salad there? No, I need salad."
And the real thing is suffering.
Tell your neighbour, “The real thing about me is not my body”.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If God revealed to you your real thing, your real self, your real value, the way it looks like,
you would quarrel, "Why am I looking so handsome; look at it. Look at my real value and the way it looks."
In John 8, the Bible says, ‘When the Son sets you free, you shall be free indeed’,
He meant the liberation of your spirit, not your body.
He meant the liberation of your spirit – man’s spirit.
This is what He meant.
It is a shame.
We live life in descending order instead of ascending order.
Everything about us like that.
You want to do this, that...
You keep doing things by yourself, not by the help of the real thing – your real self, your real value.
You keep doing many things.
You wake up; instead of consulting your real self whom the Holy Spirit works through, you abandon that.
When the Bible says, ‘When the Son sets you free, you shall be free indeed’,
it means the liberation of your spirit – man’s spirit.
I’m telling you here - look at me, two personalities here today, but you don't know.
Look here - two personalities; the one that put on the suit - good, that is Mr. T.B. Joshua,
there is also one - my real self.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You cannot get involved in God’s project without your real self.
Man is a spirit being.
You are a spirit being.
Tell your neighbour.
[You are a spirit being.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"In the name of Jesus - be healed, be delivered!"
They take time, "Who is talking there? Is it T.B. Joshua that is talking?"
If it is T.B. Joshua, he is talking to himself.
Only you will hear him, and he will hear himself - but God...
He is making noise, he is talking to air.
See the whole world today - can you see? We are lost.
When it comes to things of the Spirit, we are lost.
You don't even know whether you worship God.
Because man cannot do the work of the Cross, only God can.
When we try to do the work of the Cross by ourselves, we are inflicting pain on ourselves.
What is the pain?
Our word is meaningless, oftentimes destructive, idle - it is pain.
"I'm here today to say 'Praise the Lord. Hallelujah!'",
and I'm not sent, inspired, not by the help of Holy Spirit, and I carry the Bible and say,
"Men, hallelujah!"
You see everybody enjoying, emotional - oh my God.
I'm inflicting pain on myself.
Whatever I say that day will be meaningless, idle, oftentimes destructive.
Pain.
When I finish talking here and go back to sleep; dream, vision -
beating me, killing me, asking, "Who sent you?
What are you saying? You are talking against us. You are rebuking us. You are satan's shame.
Do you know whom you are talking to? Who sent you to say that?"
Beating you mercilessly, pain, giving you shit to eat.
When you wake up, you will not tell anyone; only you know what happened to you.
They will ride you like a bicycle, "Go to your church. Go, and preach the Word of God".
Man has the ability to preach but the Holy Spirit preaches as He wills.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Intimation must come to us from the Spirit, "Do it this way, do it that way".
Suggestion must come from above to tell you,
"OK, talk to this person, pray, stretch your hand, no, don't do that, go, look..."
Suggestion must come from the Spirit.
If not...
Corresponding power - if not, and you start doing things on your own...
Because you are well educated, you can read Bible, you understand Bible - Bible is not literature.
The Holy Spirit moved on men of old to document the Holy Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We were talking about the Book of 1 Thessalonians 5:23 -
man is a spirit being, he is a divine person possessed of spirit, soul and body.
It is possible to identify our body; what of our soul and spirit?
Shall we say we have no soul and spirit because we cannot identify them -
because there is no emotional contact to prove their existence
or there is no emotional reaction to prove their existence?
Shall we say we have no soul and spirit when God says we have?
Let me leave you with this word:
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a Christian.
Tell your neighbour.
[If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a Christian.]
No, let me put it this way; there are two Christians -
if you are not born again, born of the Spirit, you are not a true Christian.
Tell your neighbour.
[if you are not born again, born of the Spirit, you are not a true Christian.]
There must be corresponding power.
You must connect with your Father in Heaven.
A suggestion must come from above on what to do – an intimation,
if not, you will continue to live on copy.
"What did he say?"
"What do they say?"
"What is this?"
"Where should I go?"
You continue to live on copy.
When you are using a copy, and it is not original, you know how it is?
If I want to give you a book, and I make a photo-copy and give you that copy.
You continue to live a copy life.
Your business, your life, your health, your joy, your peace;
there is a copy-peace, copy-joy, copy-business, copy-happiness, copy...
Without corresponding power from above, without intimation, suggestion...
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a true Christian.
You can be the richest in the world, without the Spirit of God.
You can have the largest church, congregation all over the world, without the Spirit of God.
Listen to me.
You can have the largest church, without the Spirit of God.
The largest congregation; the crowd is not our strength.
Watch Emmanuel TV - it is the most watched channel, all over the world.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The most watched channel now - click it - all over the world.
But this is Ikotun Egbe, a very isolated city here.
But you find your way to come.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Crowd - the largest church all over the world can be operating without the Holy Spirit.
You can be the richest man of the world, without the Holy Spirit.
You can be the most famous one, all over the world, without the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Our joy, our main reward is peace of heart.
Are you with me?
How many soldiers do you see here with guns?
Do you see barricades here?
Because I have so much peace of heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are supposed to be barricades here, because somebody can jump there.
Even ushers - I don't want them standing here - go your way,
because there is so much peace of heart.
If you send me over there, you are helping me - that is my home.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are just helping me; that is my home, this is where I want to be.
Sending me there is helping, it is not anything but helping me.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What are we talking about?
All those things you see as a testimony of Holy Spirit, manifestation of Holy Spirit, this, that...
The testimony of the Holy Spirit is peace of heart.
Because you need that peace of heart, that is why you keep running.
You can't eat what you want to eat.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, I want to leave you here.
Bless you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT ROBERT BEGIER 24/08/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 24/08/2018